# Nick Little

10/200 Gloucester Street Christchurch Central Christchurch 021 047 2244 nick@nlittle.com

IT Strategist | Cloud Governance Expert | Commercially Focussed

### **Personal Profile**

Strategically minded candidate with over 10 years of IT industry experience. Containing a breadth of understanding across a number of information technology disciplines, with in-depth working knowledge of cloud computing, security protocols, data governance, high level incident resolution, backup and disaster recovery. AWS and ITIL certified leader currently working with clients to migrate on-premise systems into the AWS cloud, or enhance existing cloud solutions and operations.

Awarded Contributor for the development and implementation of ABIS (Automated Biometric Identification System) with the New Zealand Police. This project converted a paper based process used to capture the biometric information of offenders to a fully digitised system. Within the first month of digitisation the New Zealand Police observed a 30% increase of individuals being identified as repeat offenders. In the six months following officers were able to capture biometric information six times faster.

### **Highlights**

- Awarded Contributor for the development and implementation of ABIS (Automated Biometric Identification System) with the New Zealand Police.
- Managed the global integration of the 104 million dollar JBMS (Joint Management System) project.
- Colorado (USA) life science education products trainer for ADInstruments.
- IT Professionals New Zealand Presenter.
- Audacious Business Challenge Top 40 Finalist.
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner and AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate.

### **Professional Experience**

# Consegna.Cloud Cloud Solutions Architect 2021 - Present

Consegna is the first and the only NZ owned Amazon Web Services (AWS) Partner Network (APN) Premier Partner globally, and holds a number of partner competencies. I am a senior architect in the Architecture & Consultancy practice. I provide consultative cloud architectural services to a range of public and private sector clients globally, at times as part of the AWS ProServ (AWS professional services business unit).

- Direct and work alongside a team of AWS professionals to architect and ensure the appropriate strategy, solution design, and delivery of cloud solutions and migrations
- Participate in AWS commercial partner offerings including but not limited to Operational Licensing Agreements (OLA), Well Architected Reviews (WAR), Migration Acceleration Program (MAP) and secure successful AWS funding for clients
- Consultative Solution and Enterprise architecture, solution design, strategy and assurance for clients in both the public and private sector not limited to solely AWS (covering the full gamut of the project lifecycle including assisting with RFx responses, procurement, project design, management and delivery)
- Strengthening the internal architecture practices of clients and internally at Consegna with sufficient processes and governance, documentation, a focus on reusable patterns/building blocks for solution design, and implementing Cloud Center of Excellences (CCoE) in organizations
- Working to continually upskill my fellow peers and myself in order to assist Consegna retain the AWS APN Premier partner tier which has stringent requirements that have to be continually met annually
- Working directly with the SLT to assist with continual improvement in the Professional Services vertical in Consegna to ensure scalable growth, optimized resource utilization, and engaged and confident consultants.

## Ministry for Primary Industries Solutions Architect 2019 - 2021

The Ministry for Primary Industries(MPI) is a public sector organisation that employs over 3,000 staff members across 60 different locations. Working across multiple business units including Biosecurity New Zealand, Fisheries New Zealand, New Zealand Food Safety, Te Uru Rakau, and Agriculture and Investment Services. It is my responsibility to bridge the gap between business and technology.

As a Solutions Architect, I provide a helicopter view throughout the whole project lifecycle, from early inception, through to successful delivery of a project. I act as the conduit between the business, technical staff and vendor(s) at MPI. Working closely with project leads, to ensure that my architectural vision is executed in line with MPI architectural and IT strategies, and progress is continuously communicated to MPI's senior leadership team.

• Work alongside a team of three MPI Enterprise Architects to ensure projects are delivered in alignment with the MPI architectural and IT strategies.

- Provide feedback, advice and consultation to help improve and define the architectural and IT strategies at MPI.
- Define and ensure the functional and nonfunctional requirements are met by the product development/selection, and align with MPI architectural and IT strategies.
- Review and provide technical architectural advice and governance on MPI wide projects. Including but not limited to: Investment Cases, Technical Due Diligence processes, Business cases, Managing technical RFx respondents, approving and reviewing Statement of Work for vendors.
- Create architectural documentation and artifacts to comply with TOGAF and NZ all of government architecture and security best practices.
- Submission and review of documents submitted to the MPI Architectural Governance Board, and change advisory board.
- Present technical information to MPI's senior leadership team, and at investment and finance/governance meetings to gain funding approval for projects.

## Timely Limited Infrastructure Engineer 2018 - 2019

Timely Limited is an award winning start-up with 9000 customers across 81 countries. After receiving seven million dollars in funding from Movac, I was appointed as Timely's first Infrastructure Engineer to take them to the next level.

2017 Deloitte Fast 50 - Fastest Growing Technology Business. 2017 Hi-Tech Awards - Emerging Company of the Year. 2016 Microsoft Partner Awards - Rising Star. 2014 OBIZ Awards - Emerging Business Awards. 2013 Webstock BNZ Start-up Alley.

- Works with the CTO and senior leaders to develop platform, database and internal technology strategy.
- Responsible for building the internal technology roadmap, quarterly objectives and key performance indicators
- Key contributor advising on the platform and database roadmaps, quarterly objectives and key performance indicators.
- Oversees the implementation of large scale security services from proposal to inception.
- Constantly develops and improves internal user support frameworks.
- Engages with new starters through Timely's onboarding process to establish lasting relationships with individuals across all business functions.
- Drives transparent workplace culture by challenging ideas at all levels.
- Leads peers through objective decision making while building genuine relationships.

# Middleware New Zealand Limited Middleware Technical Specialist 2016 - 2017

Middleware New Zealand Limited is an award winning security and integration consultancy firm. Providing their services to high profile clients in both the private and public sectors. As a Middleware Technical Specialist I managed the global integration of the 104 million dollar JBMS (Joint Border Management System) project.

2016 Axway APAC Partner Award - Best APAC Partner Contribution.

- Final escalation point for middleware incidents.
- Technical Incident Manager responsible for restoring client business services within agreed service level agreements.
- Proactively managed high-profile client services by building rapport with key stakeholders.
- Utilised Change Management processes when implementing technical client changes.
- Consulted with clients and stakeholders to successfully deliver on agreed objectives.
- Collaborated with cross functional agile teams to perform technical project tasks with clients and external vendors.
- Applied data governance principals across high profile private and public sector clients.
- Trusted Top Secret government security clearance holder.

### NEC New Zealand Systems Engineer Global Safety Division 2015 - 2016

NEC is a global Fortune 500 Company. They are a provider of information technology services and products worth approximately 315 billion(USD) dollars. As a Systems Engineer I was a member of the global Public Safety Team and an Awarded Contributor for the development and implementation of ABIS (Automated Biometric Identification System) with the New Zealand Police.

- Key contributor of the Public Safety Team a global cross-functional agile squad responsible for delivering the ABIS, BoozeBus and LiveScan projects with the New Zealand Police.
- Final escalation point for all Public Safety Team services provided to the New Zealand Police.
- Ensured the secure transmission and storage of data extracted from the National Intelligence Agency's API to ABIS.
- Developed disaster recovery protocols for biometric data.
- Trusted partner responsible for overseeing the installation of data centre equipment and implementation of data centre solutions within shared government centres throughout New Zealand.
- Key contributor responsible for data governance.
- Trusted Top Secret government security clearance holder.

# ADInstruments Technical Support Specialist 2012 - 2015

ADInstruments is an award winning life science education products provider. As a Technical Support Specialist I was deployed to Colorado for six weeks as a product trainer.

2017 Association for Talent Development - Excellence in Practice Award for Learning Technologies.

- Provided physical training to Otago health science students on how to operate ADInstruments hardware(training mannequins) to facilitate better outcomes for future patients.
- Involved in the development of life sciences hardware and software including(but not limited to) oxygen saturation monitors, pulse transducers.
- Responsible for analysing salesforce data and providing reporting insights to the executive team and
- Identify sales and retention opportunities.
- Developed training material for life science education software products.
- Establish and maintain effective working relationships with other members of the LabTutor team, across different languages and cultures.
- Incident responder for software products.
- Incident liaison between clients, support team and developers.
- Assisted with data backups and disaster recovery operations.
- Tasked with data governance duties.

### **Education**

### Otago Polytechnic Bachelor of Information Technology 2010 - 2012

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (AWS CCP)
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect (AWS SAA)
- RedHat Certified Engineer (RHCE)
- RedHat Certified Systems Administrator (RHCSA)
- ITIL V3
- Cisco CCNA 1, 2, 3 and 4

### <u>Referees</u>

Available on request.